Register of the Victor Hoo papers, 1931-1972
Hoover Institution Archives
Victor Hoo papers
1931-1972
77046
Hoover Institution Archives
9 manuscript boxes, 1 card file box, 1 envelope, 1 sound tape reel (3.7 linear feet)
Diaries, correspondence, speeches and writings, clippings, reports, memoranda, and photographs relating to Chinese political events and foreign relations, international diplomatic conferences, Sino-Soviet relations, and the United Nations.
Hoo, Victor, 1894-1972
Access
Collection is open for research.
Use copies of all sound recordings in this collection are available.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1977.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1894 November 16 Born, Washington, D.C.
1905 Graduated from Kaiser Primary School, St. Petersburg, Russia
1912 Graduated from Annen Schule, St. Petersburg
1916 Licencie en Droit, University of Paris Law School
1918 Docteur en Droit, University of Paris Law School
1919 Assistant Secretary, Chinese Delegation to the Paris Peace Conference
1920 Member, Chinese Delegation to the Conference of Associations for the League of Nations, Brussels, Belgium Technical Member, Chinese Delegation to the International Finance Conference, Brussels
1921 Technical Delegate, Chinese Delegation to the Conference for the Suppression of Traffic in Women and Children, Geneva, Switzerland
1921-1924 Second Secretary, First Secretary, and Charge d'Affaires, Chinese Legation, Berlin, Germany
1925-1927 Returned to China Served in the Tariff Conference in Beijing as assistant director of the Treaty Department Technical Expert to the Sino-Soviet Conference and Assistant Counsellor of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs
1926 Sectional Chief, Treaty Department of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs Secretary of Cabinet
1927 Assistant Director of the Treaty Department
1928 Counsellor, Shanghai City Government Secretary, Reorganization Commission Secretary, Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the National Government
1930-1931 Director, Department of Asiatic Affairs at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs
1931 Technical Advisor, Chinese Delegation to the Sino-Soviet negotiations on the Chinese Eastern Railway Secretary General, Chinese Delegation to the Assembly of the League of Nations
1932 Director, Permanent Office of the Chinese Delegation to the League of Nations Charge d'Affaires in Switzerland Representative, League of Nations Advisory Committee on Opium and Other Dangerous Drugs
1933-1942 Envoy Extraordinary and Minister Plenipotentiary, Bern, Switzerland
1937-1942 Representative, League of Nations Advisory Committee on Social Questions
1942-1945 Returned to China and served as vice-minister of foreign affairs
1944 Delegate, Bretton Woods and Dumbarton Oaks Conferences
1945 Secretary-General, Chinese Delegation to the United Nations Conference in San Francisco Technical Expert, Sino-Soviet Conference for the Sino-Soviet Treaty of Alliance
1945-1946 Substitute Delegate, Executive Committee, Preparatory Commission and General Assembly, United Nations, London
1946 Assistant Secretary-General, United Nations, in charge of Trusteeship and Information from Non-Self-Governing Territories
1947 Special Representative of the Secretary-General, United Nations, Special Committee on Palestine (UNSCOP)
1948 Special Representative of the Secretary-General, United Nations, Temporary Commission on Korea (UNTCOK)
1955-1962 Under-Secretary for Conference Services, United Nations
1962-1972 Commissioner for Technical Co-Operation, United Nations
1972 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers of Victor Chi-tsai Hoo consist of diaries, correspondence, speeches and writings, clippings, reports, memoranda, and photographs relating to Chinese political events and foreign relations, international diplomatic conferences, Sino-Soviet relations, and the United Nations.
United Nations.; China--Foreign relations--Soviet Union.; China--Foreign relations--Switzerland.; China--Foreign relations.; China--Politics and government--1912-1949.; China.; Diplomats--China.; Phonotapes.; Russia (Federation); Soviet Union--Foreign relations--China.; Soviet Union.; Switzerland--Foreign relations--China.; Switzerland.; World War, 1939-1945--Diplomatic history.; World War, 1939-1945.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1947-1972 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Clippings, photographs, and tribute, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Scrapbook
    Loose scrapbook sheets, mainly of clippings and photographs.
    - 1947-1949 (Box-folder 1: 1)
    - 1963-1971 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Tribute, 1972 (Box-folder 1: 3)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1931-1971 (Boxes 1-2)
  Mainly letters and telegrams, arranged chronologically. Includes correspondence with Ralph Bunche, C. L. Hsia, V. K. Wellington Koo, Trygve Lie, T. Y. Lo, William E. Rappard, Syngman Rhee, David Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, T. V. Soong, Edward R. Stettinius, Jr., Adlai E. Stevenson, Sao-Ke Alfred Sze, U. Thant, and Tsune-chi Yu. Also includes some documents, particularly on the League of Nations.
  - 1931 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - 1932 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - 1933 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - 1934 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - 1935 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - 1936 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - 1937 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - 1938 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - 1939 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - 1940 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - 1941 (Box-folder 2: 3-4)
  - 1942-1945 (Box-folder 2: 5-6)
  - 1946 (Box-folder 2: 7-11)
  - 1947 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - 1949-1952 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - 1962-1965 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - 1971 (Box-folder 2: 15)
- DIARIES, 1937-1971 (Boxes 3-4)
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1937 July 20 - 1945 September 21 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - 1946 April 24 - 1949 December 30 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - 1950 January 12 - 1951 July 12 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - 1951 July 18 - 1953 March 22 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - 1953 March 29 - 1954 March 3 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - 1954 April 9 - 1958 May 24 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - 1958 July 11 - 1962 December 16 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - 1966 October 22 - 1972 March 1 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - 1967 February 23 - 1971 March (Box-folder 4: 3)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1932-1972 (Boxes 4-6)
  Broadcast transcripts, interviews, notes, speeches, and writings, arranged chronologically.
  - General
    - Undated (Box-folder 4: 4)
    - 1932 (Box-folder 4: 5)
    - 1933 (Box-folder 4: 6)
    - 1934 (Box-folder 4: 7)
    - 1935 (Box-folder 4: 8)
    - 1937 (Box-folder 4: 9)
    - 1938 (Box-folder 4: 10)
    - 1939 (Box-folder 4: 11)
    - 1940 (Box-folder 4: 12)
    - 1943 (Box-folder 4: 13)
    - 1944 (Box-folder 4: 14)
    - 1945 (Box-folder 4: 15-16)
      Includes Chunking lectures.
    - 1945 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - 1946 (Box-folder 5: 2)
    - 1947 (Box-folder 5: 3)
    - 1948 (Box-folder 5: 4)
    - 1949 (Box-folder 5: 5)
    - 1950 (Box-folder 5: 6)
    - 1951 (Box-folder 5: 7)
    - 1952 (Box-folder 5: 8)
    - 1953-1955 (Box-folder 5: 9)
    - 1957-1959 (Box-folder 5: 10)
    - 1960-1969 (Box-folder 5: 11)
    - 1970-1972 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Official
    - 1963-1964 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - 1965-1967 (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - 1968-1971 (Box-folder 6: 3)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1931-1960 (Boxes 6-8)
  Mainly correspondence, memoranda, minutes of meetings, reports, and speeches, including by Victor Hoo, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - China
    - General, 1941-1945 (Box-folder 6: 4-6)
    - Foreign relations
      - Argentina, 1945 (Box-folder 6: 7)
      - Dominican Republic, 1945 (Box-folder 6: 8)
      - Soviet Union, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Confucianism (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Narcotics, 1931-1952 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Trusteeships and non-self-governing territories, 1942-1960 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - United Nations, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 7: 4-8)
    Includes documents relating to the Bretton Woods and Dumbarton Oaks conferences, as well as to the United Nations Conference on International Organization. See also: DECLASSIFIED U.S. GOVERNMENT RECORDS.
  - United Nations (Box-folder 8: 1-4)
  - Miscellany (Box-folder 8: 5)
- TRIP REPORTS, 1963-1971 (Box 8)
  - 1963-1964 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - 1968-1971 (Box-folder 8: 7)
- CARD FILE, 1954-1972 (Box 9)
  Mainly speeches, arranged chronologically.
- SOUND RECORDING, 1963 (Tape cabinet)
  - "People at the United Nations," interview of Victor Hoo, 1963 September 14
    Access
    Use copy reference number: 77046_a_0012380
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1940s-1960s (Photo file)
  - 36 prints depicting Victor Hoo, alone and with others, especially at United Nations functions and meetings, 1940s-1960s
    General note
    See also: BIOGRAPHICAL FILE.
- DECLASSIFIED U.S. GOVERNMENT RECORDS, 1933-1946 (Box 10)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes some interfiled, unclassified government records. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover, thereunder chronologically by date of creation.
  - 2016 February release of records, 1933-1946 (Box-folder 10: 1-4)
    Correspondence, memoranda, proposals, summaries, and meeting minutes largely relating to the United Nations, especially the Dumbarton Oaks Conference.